CHARLES "CHUCK" PIERCEY

Mountain View, CA 94041 = 650.224.3429 = cpiercey@icloud.com = www.linkedin.com/in/cpiercey

OPEN COMMUNICATION

INCLUSIVE LEADERSHIP

STRATEGIC PLANNING

20+ years of high-tech product leadership success in Silicon Valley across 4 early-stage startups and multiple large companies as well as experience working on both forest sustainability and cattle disease tracking in Costa Rica.

As technology leader, advisor, and collaborator, has delivered 15+ commercial and open-source technology products to multiple markets, generating more than \$2.5B in revenue. Bridging technical and business perspectives, empowers global teams to success and mentors staff into top performers.

Skillfully manages the entire product life cycle from prototyping and testing new features to sunsetting legacy products. Designs roadmaps to illustrate product vision, and integrates multiple stakeholders' requirements into focus, prioritization, and delivery.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KIOXIA America, Inc., San Jose, CA

2019 to 2023

Director of Product Management

- Led 5-member product team located in the US and Israel for the Japanese-owned computer memory and storage products manufacturer. Coached staff to success and collaborated with cross-functional teams.
- Over 9 releases, transformed a flash storage product into a data center-class storage architecture. Key features of KumoScale included multipath storage data path routing, volume snapshots, and an analytics dashboard.
- Developed front and back end of the KumoScale website. Authored white papers, hosted and tested online technical documentation in HubSpot Knowledge Base.
- Evaluated and selected customer relationship management (CRM) tools and vendors. Implemented social media automation, metrics, and customer tracking. Designed the customer support portal.

TidalScale, Inc. (acquired by HPE), Los Gatos, CA

2012 to 2018

VP Product Management, Co-Founder

- Co-founded an inverse-hypervisor software-defined server startup, raising \$32M across Angel, series A and B funding rounds from investors including HWP, Bain, Sapphire, and Citrix.
- Invented an app for managing virtual servers that increased data center resource utilization by 10x. Defined and shipped the first 5 TidalScale Hyper Kernel versions.
- Authored 8 volumes of technical documentation, 10 white papers, 55 blog posts, and other thought leadership materials.
- Delivered 12+ successful POC engagements in hosted environments and customer sites, as field engineer. Deployed a HubSpot CRM system to drive marketing, PR, events, which generated <5K leads.

Nokia, Inc. (formerly Trolltech), Sunnyvale, CA

2007 to 2012

Director of Product Management & Business Development

- Influenced Trolltech's development pivot from desktop computers to consumer devices, which increased annual revenues from \$25M to \$150M) after conducting extensive customer research in 200+ meetings worldwide.
- Led an international staff of 35 located in the US, Europe and Asia, supporting Trolltech's hybrid open-source and commercial software Qt UI framework acquired from by Nokia at 10x valuation.
- Integrated Qt into Nokia's mobile operating system and increased the number of Nokia mobile apps by restructuring sales team compensation from Qt license-based to Nokia OS design win-based commissions.
- Argued in support of the Linux-based mobile phone software stack for which Nokia had acquired Trolltech, but Nokia CEO Stephen Elop selected Windows mobile OS instead, which led to the collapse of Nokia's mobile phone business.

Business Objects, Inc., Levallois-Perret, Paris, France

2002 to 2007

Senior Director of Product Management

- Product Managed and integrated extract transform load (ETL) tool into the Business Objects business intelligence suite.
- Defined and shipped 8 products, generating \$1.5B in revenue. Was granted 3 patents for navigating reports with versioned data, which was a differentiating product feature.
- Founded Business Objects Labs incubator to accelerate the company's ideation process, graduating 15 concepts into
 prototyped products. Invented and delivered the first mobile business intelligence app, closing beachhead deal with the US
 Army for \$1M (the app generates >\$150M revenues today).

Charles "Chuck" Piercey [page 2]

Early career experience:

Apple Developer Tools, SGI, Acta Technology and ROLM Corp., Silicon Valley, CA

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

Los Altos-Mountain View Festival of Lights Parade Association (FOLPA), manager of student internship program, Board member, float builder, parade logistics (6 years)

Deer Creeks Meadows, LLC, land development manager. Managed 100-acre Nevada City wild open space and neighborhood development project (15 years)

Wildlife Center of Silicon Valley, possums home release volunteer (5 years)

Economic Development, San Jose, Costa Rica, built database applications for clients including Costa Rica Ministry of Housing, International Institute for Cooperative Agriculture, Tikal Travel Company, and Portico Door Company (2 years)

Community Development Center, Nagarkot, Pokhara Region, Nepal, installed remote sanitation systems and smokeless stoves. Supported weekly medical clinic and distributed vegetable seeds to the local population (1 year)

PUBLICATIONS

The 12 "P"'s of Taking New Products to Market, 2023

How Kubernetes & NVMe-oF Will Rock, Medium, Nov 7, 2019

The Power of K8s-native Architecture, Medium, Jul 24, 2019

Kubernetes is a Modern BIOS for the Global Computer, Medium, Jun 7, 2019

Ego, Vulnerability & Innovation, Medium, Oct 22, 2017

Select White Papers:

7 Technology Trends Driving the Industry to Software-Defined Servers, 2018

TidalScale System Performance Analysis for R, 2018

Amdahl vs. Gustafson, 2017

PATENTS

Apparatus and Method for Facilitating Trusted Business Intelligence (8010426), Aug 2011.

Apparatus and Method for Facilitating Trusted Business Intelligence through Data Context (8046673), Oct 2011.

Apparatus and Method for Generating Reports from Versioned Data (8438140), May 2013.

Using Multidimensional Metadata Tag Sets to Determine Resource Allocation in a Distributed Computing Environment (11216309), Jan 2022.

EDUCATION

Climate Fellow, Terra.do, 2023

MBA in High Technology Startup Operations, UCLA Anderson School of Management, 1992

BA in English, Stanford University, 1984